* I don't ever want to feel *
* Like I did that day *
* Take me to the place I love *
* Take me all the way *
* I don't ever want to feel *
* Like I did that day *
* Take me to the place I lo... *
伙计们  拜托
Fellas, please.
佩妮  别这样
Penny, come on.
我们刚润好嗓子
We were just finding our sound.
确实
You found it.
听起来就像被割草机碾过的猫叫
It's the sound of a cat being run over by a lawn mower.
我真的很忙
I'm really very busy.
有没有办法延期
Is there any way that we can put this off
好让我有时间准备
until I have more time to prepare?
当然
Of course.
但你知道我害怕
But, uh, you understand my trepidation.
怎么回事
What's that about?
没头绪
Not a clue.
不能推迟到春季吗
Can't we just postpone it till the spring?
或者明年夏天
Maybe next summer?
这个很容易推断
This should be fairly easy to deduce.
他用左耳听电话
He's holding the phone to his left ear.
耳朵受同侧脑半球控制  他在用理性
Ears do not cross hemispheres, so he's using the analytical
而不是感性的大脑半球  表明
rather than the emotional side of the brain, suggesting that
他与来电方无私人感情
he has no personal relationship with the caller.
不  我没发现有这么久了
No, I didn't realize it had been so long.
当然  我看也没别的选择了 只好硬着头皮上了
Sure, I guess there's no other choice but to just go ahead and do it.
他提到的是他以前做过的事
He's referring to an activity he has done before.
令人不爽  还得反复做
It's unpleasant and needs to be repeated.
这就说明是某种
This suggests some sort of
侵入性医学检查  很可能是结肠镜检查
invasive medical test, like perhaps a colonoscopy.
没别的选择吗
Aren't there any other options?
空间不大
There's not a lot of room.
会很不舒服的
It's gonna be uncomfortable.
没错  没错
Yes, yes.
绝对是结肠镜检查
I'm definitely going with colonoscopy.
好的  拜
Okay, bye.
我母亲要来了
My mother's coming to visit.
怎么样  你说对了
How about that, you were right.
《生活大爆炸》
第二季  第15集
电梯故障了
It's out of order.
知道  我看到提示了
Yes, I can read the sign.
我在思考其含义
I'm just pondering the implications.
含义就是电梯坏了
I think it implies that the elevator doesn't work.
再说一次  我看到提示了
Again, I can read the sign.
但提示和带子上都积了一层灰
But the sign and the tape are coated with a layer of dust,
表明电梯不能用
which indicates that the elevator has been nonfunctional
有好长时间了
for a significant amount of time.
这就说明要么这楼的 24到36户人家  我假设的
Which suggests either a remarkable passivity among the, I assume,
基于邮箱的个数
24 to 36 residents of this building,
和典型的城市人口密度得出的
based on the number of mailboxes
都特别懒散
and given typical urban population density
要么都同时产生功能性错觉
or a shared delusion of functionality.
你一定是莱纳德的母亲
You must be Leonard's mother.
我不确定我一定是  但没错
Oh, I don't know if I must be, but yes.
我是佩妮  他的邻居
Uh, I'm Penny. I'm his neighbor.
贝芙莉·霍夫斯塔德博士
Oh, Dr. Beverly Hofstadter.
很高兴认识你
Oh, nice to meet you.
你喜欢握手  有趣
Oh, you're a hand shaker. Interesting.
跟我来吧
Uh, why don't you come with me.
-我带你去他公寓  -好的
I'll walk you to the apartment. Oh, all right.
路上可以寒暄寒暄吗
Would you like to exchange pleasantries on the way?
当然  我想可以
Yeah, sure, I guess.
好的  你先说
All right, you start.
好的
Okay.
我总是很好奇
You know, I've always been curious.
莱纳德小时候什么样子
What was Leonard like when he was little?
我猜你是说年幼时
Oh, I think you mean young.
他一直很小[个子矮小]
He's always been little.
好的
Right, okay.
他年幼时什么样子
What was he like when he was young?
你得说得更具体些
You'll have to be more specific.
好的  大约5  6岁时
Um, okay, like, five or six.
5岁
Five.
在那个年纪  他正陷于
Oh, well, at that age, he was well enmeshed
被弗洛伊德称之为
in what Freud would call the phallic stage
性心理发展的阴茎期
of psychosexual development.
当然是过气的理论  但这孩子的确
An outmoded theory, of course, but the boy did spend
醒着的大部分时间都紧紧地抓着"小弟弟"
most of his waking hours with a tight grasp on his penis.
莱纳德提过你以前是精神病医生
Yeah, Leonard mentioned you were a psychiatrist.
是我的学位之一
Well, that is one of my degrees.
我的主修是神经系统学
My primary field is neuroscience.
我是个演员
Well, I'm an actress.
为什么
Why?
什么为什么
What do you mean why?
有研究表明很多从事
Well, there are studies that suggest that many who go into
演艺事业的人都受外界认同的煎熬
the performing arts suffer from an external locus of identity.
我不知道那是什么意思
Yeah, I don't know what that means.
就是说只有别人看重你时 你才看重自己
Well, it means you value yourself only as others value you,
一般是童年情感需要得不到满足的结果
which is often the result of unmet childhood emotional needs.
我有个很棒的童年
Oh, well, I had a wonderful childhood.
和我说说
Tell me about it.
我知道我爸爸想要个男孩
I know my dad wanted a boy.
我就拼命让自己变成运动能手
I-I just, I tried being good at sports,
但我讨厌脏兮兮的
but I hated getting dirty!
之后  我猜  你进入青春期
And then, I'm assuming, you entered adolescence.
在我戴上少女乳罩前  他一直称我为强击手
He called me Slugger until I got my first training bra.
之后就不再和我一起打球
And then he just stopped playing catch with me.
我也不再是强击手了
I wasn't Slugger anymore.
你母亲来了
Your mother's here!
如果你想和那女孩性交
If you want to have intercourse with that girl,
查一下她父亲用哪种古龙水就行
find out what kind of cologne her fathore.
妈妈  很高兴见到您
Good to see you, Mother.
妈妈  您的茶沏好了
Here's your tea, Mother.
-乌龙茶  -是的
- Oolong? - Yes.
-散装的  不是茶包  -是的
- Loose, not bagged? - Yes.
-泡了三分钟  -是的
- Steeped three minutes? - Yes.
-百分之二的牛奶  -是的
- Two-percent milk? - Yes.
-分别加热  -是的
- Warmed separately? - Yes.
-一勺糖  -是的
- One teaspoon sugar? - Yes.
-粗糖  -是的
- Raw sugar? - Yes.
已经凉了
It's cold.
我重头再来
I'll start again.
我也觉得他有问题
I have the same problem with him.
我的理论是他不够专注
My theory is that his lack of focus
因为性欲过剩
stems from an over-developed sex drive.
我真不知道他是从哪遗传的
Oh, I don't know where he would've gotten that.
在我和他父亲圆满的婚姻之余
Aside from a pro forma consummation of our marriage,
我们只为了生育下一代 而进行性行为
his father and I only had intercourse for the purposes of reproduction.
这种安排太有效率了
That seems a fairly efficient arrangement.
我们也这么认为
Yes, we think so.
我们都因此发表了论文
We've both done papers on it.
我的论文是从神经系统科学的角度写的
Mine from the neuroscientific point of view
他父亲是从人类学的角度
and his from an anthropological.
当然  只有我的论文值得一读
Mine, of course, was the onlyne worth reading.
必然的
Of course.
我很有兴趣拜读您的性生活
I would very much like to read about your sex life.
我放在网上了  你也可以
Well, it's all online or you can order it
从普林斯顿大学出版社订购
from the Princeton University Press.
母亲  请喝茶
Here's your tea, Mother.
你们在聊什么呢
So, what are you guys talking about?
你父母性行为的频率
The frequency with which your parents had intercourse.
一流
Swell.
如果你三生有幸  她可能
If you're lucky, maybe she'll show you
会给你看演讲的幻灯片
the PowerPoint presentation.
不好意思  存在我另一台笔记本里
I'm sorry, it's on my other laptop.
那么  母亲
So, Mother...
有什么新鲜事么
what's new?
你要说得具体点
You'll have to be more specific.
好吧
All right.
您有什么新鲜事么
Uh, what's new with you?
我目前 出现了一些奇妙的更年期症状
Oh, well, I've been having some fascinating menopausal symptoms recently.
能谈谈不这么私人的吗
Maybe something less personal.
你叔叔弗洛德死了
Your Uncle Floyd died.
天啊
Oh, my God.
发生什么事了
What happened?
他的心跳停止了
His heart stopped beating.
我得去排尿了
I have to urinate.
真是个超赞的女人
What a remarkable woman.
我也觉得你们会很投缘
Yeah, I-I thought you guys might hit it off.
我真嫉妒你的童年生活
I envy you your childhood.
真不想告诉你  我童年唯一的美好回忆
I hate to tell you, but the only warm memories
都是和我叔叔弗洛德在一起的
I have of my childhood are of my Uncle Floyd.
你记错了吧
You're clearly misremembering.
你母亲聪明绝顶
Your mother is brilliant,
具有高超的分析力和洞察力
analytical, insightful.
我打赌就算你不肯吃汤菜
And I'm betting she never hit you with a Bible because
她也不会用圣经打你
you wouldn't eat your Brussels sprouts.
谢尔顿  你对你母亲的评价有失偏颇
Sheldon, you don't give your mother enough credit.
她是个有爱心的人
She's warm, she's loving,
她不会在你脑袋上贴上电极
she doesn't glue electrodes to your head
当你学着上厕所时测量你的脑电波
to measure your brain waves while potty training.
你很幸运
You were lucky.
我小的时候  如果想做脑电图扫描
When I was a kid, if I wanted an EEG,
我不得不自己贴电极
I had to attach my own electrodes.
霍夫斯塔德博士
So, Dr. Hofstadter,
莱纳德很少谈及
Leonard rarely talks about
他成就颇高的姐姐和弟弟
his incredibly successful brother and sister.
拜托  霍华德  别提这个了
Please, don't go there, Howard.
我了解到
I understand that,
不像莱纳德  他们 都是各自领域的权威人物
unlike Leonard, they're at the top of their respective fields.
你个烂人
Boy, you suck.
莱纳德的弟弟迈克尔
Well, Leonard's younger brother, Michael,
是哈佛的法学终身教授
is a tenured law professor at Harvard,
他的姐姐刚刚成功地
and his sister just successfully grew
在一只青春期的长臂猿体内植入人类胰脏
a human pancreas in an adolescent gibbon.
她很快就能治愈糖尿病了
So, she's close to curing diabetes?
在一只十几岁的长臂猿体内植入胰脏还有别的原因么
Why else would you grow a pancreas in a teenaged gibbon?
你一定很为他们骄傲吧
Wow, you must be very proud.
为什么
Why?
又不是我的成就
They're not my accomplishments.
我得去排尿了
I have to urinate.
你为什么这么做
Why are you doing this?
你知道游戏规则
You know the rules.
你带母亲来上班  就等着受罪吧
You brought your mom to work-- you must suffer.
莱纳德  我不知道
Leonard, I had no idea
你兄妹的成就都比你高这么多
your siblings were so much more successful than you.
你就像是霍夫斯塔德家族里的怪物查查比[星战里的马脸怪物]
Yeah, you're like the Jar Jar Binks of the Hofstadter family.
我觉得[模仿查查比的牙买加口音] 你看起来好悲哀
Oh, meesa think yousa lookin' so so sad.
我的朋友不该嘲笑我
You know, rather than mock me, my friends might realize
应该懂得我有多难  尽力帮我
that this is difficult and try to help me through it.
我觉得嘲笑你更有趣
Nope, I think mocking you is more fun.
下一次  看你还带不带妈妈来上班
Next time, don't yousa bring mama to work.
如何
Okee-day?
很快嘛
That was fast.
中间的坑被人占了
Oh, the middle stall was occupied.
我得一会再去
I'll have to try again later.
非常能理解
That's totally understandable.
排空膀胱  就好像搞房地产
In bladder voiding, as in real estate,
地点最重要
it's location, location, location.
说到哪了
So, where were we?
霍华德还和老妈住在一起   而拉杰不喝醉 就不会和女人说话
Howard lives with his mother and Raj can't speak to women unless he's drunk.
说吧
Go.
很吸引人
That's fascinating.
选择性缄默症非常稀有
Selective mutism is quite rare.
另一方面  一个成年犹太男性
On the other hand, an adult Jewish male
和母亲同住已经普遍到
living with his mother is so common
近似于社会学的陈词滥调了
it borders on sociological cliché.
只是暂时的  我有付房租
It's just temporary; I pay rent.
他现在的房间就是以前放婴儿床的
He lives in the same room where his bassinet was.
无论是选择性缄默症
You know, both selective mutism
还是无法离开母亲独自生活
and an inability to separate from one's mother
都可能是源于对女性的病理性恐惧
can stem from a pathological fear of women.
这或许可以解释为何
It might explain why
你们俩建立一段同性恋代替性婚姻关系
the two of you have created an ersatz homosexual marriage
来满足自己对亲密关系的饥渴
to satisfy your need for intimacy.
你说什么
Say what?
那不是等于我说的嘛
That's basically what I just said.
你带你"老公"一起工作
You brought your husband to work.
你知道游戏规则
You know the rules.
我觉得你们现在看起来也很悲哀  对吧
Meesa thinking yousa looking pretty sad now too, betcha, betcha.
莱纳德  已经1点了
Leonard, it's 1:00.
1点不是要带我参观你的实验室吗
Weren't you going to show me your laboratory at 1:00?
别急  妈妈
There's no hurry, Mother.
再说一点他们之间的"地下恋情"
Tell them more about their secret love for each other.
但已经1点了
But it's 1:00.
你应该在1点带我去参观你的实验室
You were going to show me your laboratory at 1:00.
她的理由无懈可击
Her reasoning is unassailable.
已经1点了
It is 1:00.
好吧  咱们走
Fine. Let's go.
你肯定会觉得我的工作很有趣
I think you'll find my work pretty interesting.
我正在尝试复制意大利人从碘化钠晶体里
I'm attempting to replicate the dark matter signal
找到的暗物质信号
found in sodium iodide crystals by the Italians.
没有原创性研究
So, no original research?
没有
No.
那我去看还有什么意义
Well, what's the point of my seeing it?
我直接看意大利人的报导不就行了
I could just read the paper the Italians wrote.
强烈声明
Just for the record,
我们没有什么同性恋代替性关系
we're not in an ersatz homosexual relationship.
你刚怎么不跟她说
Well, then why didn't you say that to her?
为什么这老是我的责任
Why is it always my responsibility?
并非老是你的责任
It's not always your responsibility.
我保证  这和你上周在漫画书店干的事情没两样
I swear, this is the same thing you did at the comic book store last week.
难以置信你会提起这件事
I can't believe you're bringing that up.
才不是我提的  是你才对
I didn't bring it up. You did.
我们以后再说
We'll talk about this later.
你老这么糊弄我  从来没这么做过
You always say that, but we never do.
你们居然去漫画书店不带上我
You went to the comic book store without me.
你有酒吗
You got alcohol?
-你老妈还没走  -没错
Your mom still here? Yep.
进来吧
Come on in.
等等  她不会来这儿找你吧
Wait, wait, she's not gonna come here looking for you, is she?
别担心  她拖了谢尔顿去医院做脑扫描
Relax. She took Sheldon to the hospital to get a brain scan.
天啊  怎么了
Oh, my God. What happened?
没什么  老妈喜欢观察大脑
Nothing. Mother likes looking at brains
谢尔顿则想做脑扫描
and Sheldon likes getting his brain scanned.
一个愿打  一个愿挨
Geez, what a fun couple.
她只在这儿呆了一天半
She's only been here a day and a half
我已经开始认真考虑把酒精中毒
and I'm seriously considering alcoholism
作为我下半生的事业
as a new career path.
我昨天只和她聊了5分钟
Hey, I talked to her for five minutes yesterday
就一直处于半醉状态
and I've been half bombed ever since.
你不能让她进驻你的大脑
You can't let her get into your head.
我的大脑  那你的呢
My head, what about yours?
已经太迟了
It's too late for me.
我的大脑就是她的避暑山庄
My head is her summer house.
可她并没有错
She was right, you know.
外界对我的认同都写在脸上了
The locus of my identity is totally exterior to me.
已经被她洗脑了  你好  老妈
Oh, yeah, there she is. Hi, Mom.
你知道我整个早上去哪了吗
I mean, do you know where I was all morning?
和50个金发美女抢试镜
Auditioning with 50 other blondes
为了一个愚蠢的抗抑郁药广告
for some stupid antidepressant commercial.
为了什么
And for what?
就为了最终得到我爸的认可
So I'll finally get my daddy's approval?
你抢到那个角色了吗
Did you get the part?
没有  他们说我太活泼了
No, they said I was too perky.
你想谈谈没有亲情的生活
You want to talk about not getting love from a parent.
你知道我的小时候
You know what I used to do when I was little
想获得人体接触做了什么吗
to have some sensation of human contact?
知道  你死抓着"小弟弟"不放
Yeah, you grabbed your penis and wouldn't let go.
你老妈告诉我的
Your mother told me.
不出所料
Of course she did.
但我想说的不是这个
Anyway, that's not what I was gonna say.
我10岁时 造了一个"拥抱机"
When I was ten years old, i built a hugging machine.
"拥抱机"
A hugging machine?
对  我找了个裁缝用的假人
Yeah. I got a dressmaker's mannequin,
在里面塞一条电热毯
I stuffed it with an electric blanket
就能有温度  还装了两只无线电控制的手臂
so it would be warm, and built two radio-controlled arms
能抱我  拍我的背
that would hug me and pat my back.
好悲哀
Oh, that is so sad.
-你知道最悲哀的是什么吗  -什么
You know what the saddest part was? What?
我爸爸常把它借过去
My father used to borrow it.
你的扫描资料会对我的研究非常有帮助
Your scan data will be very helpful to my research.
你有一颗非比寻常的大脑
You have a remarkable brain.
必须的
I know.
虽然我不喜欢我的右额叶
Although I've always hated
在X光片上的效果
how my right frontal lobe looks in pictures.
男人抱怨最多的
Common complaint among men.
总嫌东西不够大
Nothing's ever big enough.
除非是个肿瘤
Except when they get a tumor.
你就不会听到这种抱怨了
Then you never hear the end of it.
希望改日能看看你的脑扫描
I'd love to see a scan of your brain sometime.
我会发个链接给你
Oh, I'll send you a link,
但就生理学来说  我的脑扫描相当无趣
but its physiology is fairly unimpressive.
真难以置信
Oh, I can't believe that.
你不愿接受经验实据
Your unwillingness to accept empirical evidence
说明一种奉承之举
suggests an attempt at flattery.
我抱歉
My apologies.
我和你儿子住在一起太久了
I've been living with your son too long.
染了些坏习惯
Gotten into some bad habits.
可以理解
Understandable.
-能给你沏杯茶吗  -我怀疑你的能力
Can I make you a cup of tea? I doubt it,
不过有机会的人只有你了
but if anyone has a chance, it's probably you.
和你呆在一起很舒服
I feel very comfortable around you.
我也有同感
I feel very comfortable around you, too.
令人吃惊
It's surprising
因为我通常跟任何人在一起都觉得
because I generally don't feel comfortable around,
不舒服
well, anyone.
我也是
Nor I.
像我们这么独特的两个人
What are the odds that two individuals
通过像你儿子这样的庸人
as unique as ourselves would be connected
而联系上的几率有多大
by someone as comparatively workaday as your son?
那是个修辞学观点呢
Is that a rhetorical point
还是你想算算
or would you like to do the math?
我想算一算
I'd like to do the math.
我也想
I'd like that, too.
好了  这次
Okay, now this time, Uh-huh.
你要舔掉我脖子的盐
you're gonna lick the salt...off my neck...
喝一杯
...do the shot...
再咬一口酸橙
...and then bite the lime.
抱歉  "舔"后的我都没听到
I'm sorry, I didn't hear anything after "lick."
脖子  酒  酸橙
Neck, shot, lime.
好了  酒  酸橙
Okay, shot, lime.
对
Right.
酸橙在哪
Where's the lime?
我们一起吃
Oh, okay, we're sharing.
你觉得怎样
So, what do you think?
我被深深吸引了
I'm very tempted.
我只是不确定和我儿子的室友 是否合适
I'm just not sure it's appropriate with my son's roommate.
通常  我也会有同感
Normally, I'd feel the same way.
不过从我们身上的一切来看
But based on everything I've observed about us,
我无法自持地推测我们俩会很适合
I can't help but speculate we'd be very good together.
确实  我也这样觉得
True. I've had a similar observation.
绝对是我和我老公都没做过的事
It's certainly something I could never do with my husband.
第一次尝试时我也很犹豫
I was hesitant the first time I tried it,
但我体验了一次未曾料到的
but I experienced an unanticipated
大量的安多芬[能产生快感]释放
and remarkable release of endorphins.
非常令人满意
It's quite satisfying.
我明白你的用意
I see what you're doing.
你很想对我做神经学研究
You're appealing to the neuroscientific researcher in me.
你完全看穿我了  不是吗
You see right through me, don't you?
只能在电脑断层扫描仪上
Only when you're in a CAT scanner.
梦想就要成真了
This is actually gonna happen.
亲爱的  嘘  嘘  嘘
Honey, shush, shush, shush, shush, shush.
你嘘嘘  我开心  我想说
You shush, I'm happy. I want to talk about it.
你知道我妈会说什么吗
You know what my mother would say about this?
她会说  你爸爸不爱你
She would say because you were not loved by your father
我妈妈也不爱我
and I was not loved by my mother,
做爱是我们弥补儿时没有得到的 亲密关系的方法
that having sex is our way of making up for the intimacy we didn't get as children.
你为什么现在要提这个
Why would you bring that up right now?
我不知道
I don't know.
前戏吗
Foreplay?
也就是说 你不是在和我做爱
So you're saying you're not having sex with me,
是和你妈做爱吗
you're having sex with your mother?
我想说"不是"
I'm gonna go with "no."
这是我听过最恶心的事了
That is the sickest thing I've ever heard.
得了吧  你不也是想和你爸爸做爱  我都没意见
Come on, you're trying to have sex with your father, and I'm okay with that.
滚出去
Get out!
她说"嘘"  我就应该闭嘴
She said shush. I should have shushed.
* Ooh, all night, all night *
* Oh, every night *
* Hold tight * * Hold tight *
* You hold tight * * Hold tight *
* Baby, hold tight *
* Anyway you want it, that's the way you need it *
好了  妈妈
All right, Mother.
一路顺风
Um, have a nice flight.
那又不是我能控制的
That's not really in my control, is it?
早上好
Oh, good morning.
Morning.
我刚想过来和你谈谈
Look, I was just coming over to talk to you.
没必要
You don't have to.
永远
Ever.
明白
Gotcha.
再见  妈妈
Good-bye, Mother.
再见  伦纳德
Good-bye, Leonard.
强击手   我们继续 上次没说完的话题吧
So, Slugger, shall we pick up where we left off last time?
我妈妈完全可以说
I mean, my mom could've just said,
鲍勃  想开点  她只是个小姑娘
"Bob, get over it, she's a girl, move on."
但她没有
But she didn't.
-一个字也没说  -很有趣
- Not one word. - Interesting.
你能不能乘飞机去新泽西做个脑部扫描
Would you be willing to fly to New Jersey and discuss
顺便谈谈你和父母的关系吗
your relationship with your parents during a brain scan?
-会有帮助吗  -对我有帮助
- Would it help? -Well, it would help me.